-=圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品=-
淡然 作品   bbs.cnscg.com
England, in the year 1215,
1215年 英格兰
had been under the reign of King John for 16 years.
已被约翰王统治了16年
The most villainous of England's monarchs,
作为英格兰最残暴的君王
John was renowned for losing wars with France,
约翰王因对法战争的失利
levying punitive taxes,
苛捐重税
and sleeping with the wives of barons.
以及与男爵妻子有染而臭名昭著
The barons finally rebelled against their king,
最终 男爵们开始反抗他们的国王
and became locked in a bloody civil war
发动了一场血腥的内战
lasting for over three years and decimating both armies.
在长达三年的内战中 双方军队都伤亡惨重
In time, the Knights Templar were drawn into this conflict.
当时 圣殿骑士团也卷入了这场战争
With the help of these highly trained warrior monks,
在这些训练有素的修道士的帮助下
King John and his royal army were eventually defeated.
男爵们最终打败了约翰王和他的皇家军队
It was agreed that John could remain on the throne,
最终谈判决定 约翰王可以继续在位
on one condition...
但有一个条件...
that he would sign a document
他必须要签署一份文件
upholding the rights and privileges of all free men,
不仅保证所有自由人民的各项权利
but ultimately limiting the power of the monarchy.
并从根本上抑制王权
Make it count.
君无戏言
The Magna Carta was sealed at Runnymede
1215年6月15日 在兰尼米德
on the 15th of June in the year of our Lord 1215.
大宪章正式签订
It will be remembered throughout history.
这一时刻将会被历史铭记
What is not remembered is what King John did next.
然而约翰王的后续举动却被人们淡忘
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 岸
翻译: RK翔 onebyone Ivy 发条橙
校对: 不想论文的微 不想工作的岸
Sire?
陛下?
It's time.
时间到了
Hyah!
驾!
Hyah! Hyah!
驾! 驾!
England welcomes you.
英格兰欢迎你
Does the Pope hold his word?
教皇是否会信守承诺?
Oh, how have faith, Captain Tiberius.
哦 要有信心 Tiberius队长
His Eminence is waiting to hear you hold to yours.
他正期待得知你履行诺言
The Church will stay out of your lands, you have his word.
他向你保证 教会不会踏上你的领土
We'll get your country back.
我们会夺回你的国家
What say you?
所来何事?
Abbot Marcus. We seek shelter from the storm.
我是Marcus修道院长 希望能够避雨
Open the gates!
打开城门!
Come and help.
快过来帮忙
What business do you have here?
你们有何贵干?
Our business is with God at Canterbury.
我们要去坎特伯雷(英国国教的圣地)拜谒大主教
We need only shelter.
我们只想避雨
Shelter you shall have. Food also.
我们会为你提供住所 以及食物
You treat the Lord's servants well.
多谢您善待上帝的仆人
You wear the mark of the Templars, yet you carry no swords.
你们佩戴着圣殿骑士的标记 但没有佩剑
These men have no more need to fight.
他们没有必要再战斗了
Templars masking their faith and travelling without swords.
圣殿骑士标示信条 出行无须配剑
How noble!
好高尚!
As God is our witness, Baron, these men have nothing to hide.
上帝为证 男爵 这些人无需隐藏
Abbot, save your benedictions. The Templars fought against the King.
院长 别说好话了 圣殿骑士对抗国王
Now you sleep in a king's castle. These men have plenty to hide.
如今你们住在国王的城堡里 他们要隐藏的东西多了
You there. What say you?
你啊 你在做什么?
They say nothing. They hold vows of silence.
他们不说话 他们在履行沉默的誓言
Templars without tongues. Very well.
不会说话的圣殿骑士 很好
Just be gone by the morning.
明早就离开吧
Back inside!
进去!
Marshal.
Marshal啊
When I accept guardianship over men who take the vows of silence,
我接受监护发誓沉默的人任务之时
I'm also informed of what led them to me in the first place.
我也知道了为何最初选中了我
I know the Templars placed a heavy burden on you.
我知道圣殿骑团士让你身负重担
I know you're deeply scarred.
我知道你伤痕累累
The cross on your tunic
你外衣上的十字架
is a symbol of your faith in God's will.
象征你信仰上帝
It should not be full of the torment, it now bears upon your soul.
它不应带来痛苦 但现在却折磨着你的灵魂
When we arrive at Canterbury,
等我们到达坎特伯雷
I'm requesting your leave from the Order of the Knights Templar.
我会要求你离开圣殿骑士团
Garrison men!
守军!
King John!
约翰王!
Men, to the gates! It's the King!
来人 打开城门! 是国王!
Open the gates for the King!
为国王打开城门!
Marshal, did you see royal colours?
Marshal 你看到皇家旗帜了吗?
Is that your hand, Darnay?
Darnay 这是你的笔迹吗?
Forced, Your Highness.
我是被逼的 陛下
The barons threatened my life, forcing me to sign it and betray you.
男爵们以性命相要挟 强迫我签名背叛您
I know the feeling.
我深有体会
Hang him!
绞刑!
This insanity must cease.
必须阻止这疯狂的行径
Open the door. His quarrel is not with us.
开门 他和我们并无冤仇
If you three stand before the King, there will be nothing but death.
如果你们三个出现在国王面前 那就只有死路一条
What good fortune, Darnay. It seems you will have your last rites.
真幸运啊 Darnay 看来你可以做临终祈祷了
My Lord, Templars.
陛下 圣殿骑士
He's travelling en route to Canterbury with Templars.
他和圣殿骑士一起 准备去往坎特伯雷
To what do I owe the pleasure of the Church visiting my castle?
我有何荣幸 能让教会的人造访我的城堡?
We were in the storm, Sire. Baron Darnay granted us your hospitality.
陛下 我们遇到了暴雨 Darnay男爵展示了您的仁慈关爱
- We?  - My fellow priests.
- 我们?  - 与我同行的神父
Ah, yes, I heard.
啊 是 我听到的
Templars.
圣殿骑士
Sire, we entered your castle as unarmed men. We seek no fight.
陛下 我们进城时未带任何武器 我们不想引起争端
Are you aware, Abbot,
修道院长 你有没有意识到
that your kind stood at Runnymede and forced my signature,
是你们这群人在兰尼米德 强迫我签字
and now you sleep under my roof?
而如今你却休憩在我的屋檐之下
Your Highness, we travel to Canterbury
陛下 我们遵守教规
with simple articles of faith.
前往坎特伯雷
I ask your mercy that we may pass.
请您恩准我们通行
And I will grant you the same mercy
我赐予你的仁慈
that the Church and the barons of this country bestowed unto me.
与教会和男爵们给予我的一样
"Do unto others", isn't that right, Abbot?
"己所不欲 勿施于人" 不是吗 修道院长?
Tiberius!
来人 Tiberius!
Don't let them go!
别放走他们!
Ride!
快走!
There is worth...
每个人...
in every death.
都会死得其所
And I will see it now in yours.
我必将看到你离去的意义
- You saw the King?  - Yes. And he saw me.
- 你亲眼看到了国王?  - 是的 而且他也看到我了
I didn't imagine that even he was capable of such cruelty.
我不敢想象他竟然如此残暴
Abbot Marcus was the finest of men.
Marcus院长是我见过最好的人
Tell me, why did he request that you leave the Order?
告诉我 他为什么要求你脱离圣殿骑士团?
- Your Grace, I did not wish to be dismissed.  - But that's not what I asked.
- 主教大人 我不想离职  - 这不是我的问题
You were in the Holy Lands?
你曾经到过耶路撒冷?
Hm. Some men have returned from defending our faith
嗯 有些人为捍卫信仰而去
only to find themselves questioning it.
回来却发现自己对此产生了质疑
Now you must ask yourself, Thomas...
Thomas 你必须扪心自问...
what is in your heart?
你心里有的是什么?
Rebellion or revenge.
反抗还是复仇
I suppose it makes no difference as the King has the devil in his.
有个内心邪恶的国王 我想这两者没什么区别了
I don't care if he's talking to the Pope! I have to see him now!
就算他在和教皇谈话我也不管! 我现在就要见他!
And as we speak of the devil...
说到邪恶...
My Lord Archbishop.
尊敬的大主教大人
They told me about Darnay.
他们和我说了Darnay的事
We took John at his word...
我们相信了约翰的话...
and now he raises a bitch's army with God's teeth.
如今他以上帝之名集结了一队狗娘养的军队
I'll bow to no king with piss for blood!
我不向这种猪狗不如的国王屈膝!
Baron William de Albany, Brother Thomas Marshal.
William de Albany男爵 这是Thomas Marshal兄弟
Brother Thomas comes directly from Darnay Castle.
Thomas兄弟由Darnay城堡而来
You must forgive our Baron, Brother Thomas,
请原谅男爵 Thomas兄弟
his tongue is not always so profane.
男爵说话很少如此粗俗
Now, you should know that Rome sides with the King.
如今 你们应该知道罗马教廷站在国王那边
And the Pope would bless what the King did to Abbot Marcus?
教皇为国王对Marcus院长所做的一切祈福?
More or less.
差不多
I am to be excommunicated for writing Magna Carta .
我因撰写了大宪章 将被开除教籍
- How long have we got?  - God knows.
- 我们还有多少时间?  - 天知道
Your Grace, this...
主教大人 必须...
king... must be stopped.
有人... 阻止国王
I cannot, in all honesty, ask you to fight, Thomas,
老实说 我不能要求你去战斗 Thomas
but if you choose to take up your sword, you have my blessing.
但是如果你要拿起武器 我会为你祈祷
It's a good omen.
这是个好兆头
God is with us.
上帝与我们同在
Prince Louis has an army may be persuaded to join us.
也许我们能说服路易王子(法国国王路易八世)发兵支援我们
Asking the French for help...
向法国人求助...
that's cursing the blind for the wicked.
那就好像是病急乱投医
If John takes the Dover Road to London
如果约翰取道多佛尔大道前往伦敦的话
he has to cross the Medway here at Rochester.
他就必须要穿过梅德韦河 到达罗彻斯特城堡
I'll seize Rochester Castle.
我会先占领罗彻斯特城堡
Delay them. That'll give you time to negotiate with the French.
拖住他们 这样您就有时间与法国人谈判了
We have no force to fight the King.
我们没有军队对抗国王
I have a few men I can count on.
我有几个可以信赖的人
Absolutely not. Suicide is a sin in the eyes of the Church, Baron.
绝对不行 男爵 在教会看来 自杀是一种罪过
Your Grace, I'm afraid I only see one thing.
主教大人 我发现了一件事
From Rochester, the King is able to dispatch his troops and supplies
国王能够从罗彻斯特城堡向全国派兵遣将
all over the country.
补给物资
It is his keystone. Without it we will not stop him.
这是他的基石 失去此地 将无法阻止他
All my sins to this.
我所有的罪孽都源于此
May God protect what we are about to do.
愿上帝保佑我们的行动
Guy!
Guy啊!
Squire!
护卫!
I want you to ride back.
我要你回去
No. I know how to fight.
不 我知道如何战斗
You see how he talks to me?
你看到他怎么和我说话吗?
Have you ever killed a man, Squire? Eh?
你杀过人吗 护卫? 嗯?
Then you will learn, it is not a noble thing.
到时候你就知道 这绝对不是件高尚的事情
Not even when it's for freedom?
即使是为自由而战?
Not even when it is for God.
即使是为上帝而战
Hah!
驾!
Look at you!
看看你!
Any one of you throws a turd or a bean, I'll get you!
不论是谁向我扔狗屎或者豆子 我都不会放过你!
And you know I will!
你们知道我会的!
- Where's the butchers?  - Over there.
- 屠夫在哪里?  - 那里
I'll remember your faces!
我会记住你的样子!
Sheep shears! They're sharp! Sharp sheep shears!
羊毛剪! 够锋利啊! 锋利的羊毛剪!
- I'm looking for Daniel Marks.  - Wait here.
- 我找Daniel Marks  - 在这里等着
Marks!
Marks啊!
Whatever it is or how much...
不管什么事 不管多少钱...
- just get me out of here, Baron.  - Done. Where's de Lacy?
- 只要能让我离开这里 男爵  - 行 Lacy在哪里?
- He went back to Poitou  - Becket?
- 他回到Poitou了  - Becket呢?
You don't want him.
你不会想带上他的
Templars. They've come back.
圣殿骑士 他们回来了
Here. You may need protection.
拿着 你需要东西防身
Get up.
起来
I said, get up!
我说了 起来!
You sack of shit!
你个贱人!
Billy.
Billy啊
What told me I'd see you?
你找我什么事?
What's with the altar boy?
这个教会的人怎么也在?
Billy all tied up with God again?
Billy又要为信仰而战了?
- This is not our man.  - Hoy!
- 他不是我们需要的人  - 嗬!
I'm his man, don't you worry about that.
我是他的人 你不需要担心
If he pays me enough, I'll split the gut of any man alive.
只要他给的够多 我愿意活扒了所有人
Ain't that right, Billy boy?
没说错吧 Billy?
- Who's with you?  - Gil Becket. Daniel Marks.
- 你还找了谁?  - Gil Becket和Daniel Marks
The last time we were all together must have been Dieppe.
上次我们聚首还是在迪耶普(法国城市)
The days when the King was still good to us.
那时候国王待我们还很好
He's taken all the castles along the coast.
他已经占领了沿岸的所有城堡
If he takes Rochester, he'll control southern England.
如果再占领罗彻斯特城堡 他就能控制整个英格兰南部
If the whispers I've heard are true, he's too strong now.
如果我听到的消息是真的 他现在太强大了
He's got an army of Danish mercenaries.
他有一支丹麦佣军
Wait for him in London.
在伦敦等着他吧
Do you think I want this? I'm not a soldier, not any more.
你以为我想这样吗? 我不再是个战士了
I'm a fat wool merchant with a hen-pecking wife and three daughters.
我只是个发福的羊毛商人 有个碎嘴的妻子和三个女儿
But, unfortunately, he won't let it be.
但是 不幸的是 国王他不愿这样
I'm sorry, Baron. Not this one.
对不起 男爵 这次不行
I learnt about the Crusades.
我知道十字军的事
Is it true what the Templar swords say?
圣殿骑士的剑上写的是真的吗?
"Blessed and omnipotent is the warrior of Christ" ?
"基督的战士是被祝福的 他们无所不能"?
Yeah, water. Water.
好的 水 给我水
- Hey!  - Agh!
- 嘿!  - 啊!
What do you think he's worth?
你觉得他哪里值得了?
- Are you sorry for what you've done?  - Bollocks.
- 对你的所作所为感到内疚吗?  - 胡说
- Release him.  - Amen!
- 放了他  - 阿门!
Papa!
爸爸!
Get inside. Now!
回屋子里去 快!
- Joseph.  - Baron.
- 好 Joseph  - 男爵
- Daniel.  - Wulfstan.
- Daniel  - 你好 Wulfstan
Becket.
Becket 你好
You... are a filthy whore, Becket.
你... 是个下流的贱人 Becket
So was she.
她也是
We'll never hold that castle with this lot.
就我们这些人守不住城堡的
They may not be worthy of that cross you wear,
他们也许配不上你佩戴的十字架
but they'll hold the castle.
但是他们能守住城堡
Not for England... not for God...
不为英格兰... 不为上帝...
but for me.
而是为了我
Winter's soon, so if I'm not back by first snowfall,
冬天快来了 如果下第一场雪的时候 我还没有回来
take your sister to your aunt, give her this.
带着你的妹妹去找你姑姑 把这个给她
Work hard.
努力干活
Be polite.
要有礼貌
And what's written here is true?
这上面写的是真的?
From my ears to this paper, Sire.
我亲耳所闻 陛下
Tiberius, six of your fastest scouts to Rochester.
Tiberius 派6名最快的侦察兵到罗彻斯特城堡
Instruct them to hold the castle.
告诉他们 守住城堡
- Kill anyone they find there.  - Hyah!
- 杀掉找到的所有人  - 驾!
Money.
钱
How do you know these men?
你怎么认识他们?
So what does that make you?
你为什么那么做?
Worthless.
没用的家伙
There it is.
就是那里
Looks small from here.
从这看真小
That... small castle...
那座... 小小的城堡...
controls all the land as far as you can see.
控制着你目光所及的这片土地
Be patient, Squire.
耐心点 护卫
As long as there's women.
只要那里有女人
- What say you?  - I bring business from Archbishop Langton.
- 所来何事?  - 兰顿大主教派我来的
Isabel!
喂Isabel!
We have company.
有客人在
I have told you before, I will not tolerate drinking.
我告诉过你 我不能容忍你喝酒
You won't tolerate anything.
你什么都不能容忍
My lord. We have men at the gate.
大人 有人想进城
I tolerate the politics of the King, Isabel.
我容忍国王的政见 Isabel
Our marriage was arranged for land and wealth.
我们的婚姻是为了土地和财富
It would be well if you were to remember that.
只要你谨记这点 就万事大吉了
And he owns us, body and soul.
他拥有我们 身体和灵魂
Open the gates! Let them in!
打开大门! 让他们进来!
You arrive unexpected, Baron de Albany.
Albany男爵 你不期而至
What matter does His Grace send this late?
大主教因何事派你们而来?
That we claim this castle in the name of the rebellion.
以反抗军的名义接管这座城堡
If your visit is to claim my castle, Baron...
如果你是为了占有我城堡而来 男爵...
you're too late.
太迟了
Unusual saddles.
少见的马鞍
- Danish.  - What was that?
- 丹麦人  - 什么意思?
They're Danish. They arrived last night.
是丹麦人的 他们昨晚到的
The King's scouts. His army is less than a day away.
这是国王的侦察兵 大军还有不到一天就到了
Oaks, get the guard here quickly.
Oaks 快叫卫兵过来
That one was at Darnay Castle two days ago.
那家伙两天前在Darnay城堡
No, no, no!
不 不 不!
Marshal, down!
Marshal 趴下!
Baron.
男爵
Stand down! Stand down!
住手! 住手!
Listen to me.
听我说
By the archbishop, we claim this castle in the name of the rebellion.
奉大主教之令 我们以反抗之名占领这座城堡
The rebellion's over. The King surrendered to the great charter.
反抗已经结束了 国王已签署大宪章
Magna Carta.
大宪章
This one sealed by the King's own hand.
这是国王亲自签署的
And now... he's executing everybody who supported it.
现在... 他却要处死支持这份宪章的人
But does the Pope know that the Archbishop is claiming royal castles, against the King?
但教皇知道大主教要占领这座城堡 背叛国王吗?
I watched as three of my brothers were killed
我亲眼见到三位兄弟
by the soft hand of a king
被国王杀害
that is murdering his way across the country.
他正在国内掀起一场大屠杀
And he does so with the Pope's blessing.
教皇却祝福他的所作所为
The French army make sail any day now.
法国军队随时都会起航
Giving us... a new king.
选出... 一位新国王
A true king.
一位真正的国王
Seal the gates.
关上城门
Lock all the doors! Move! And, Oaks, no one else comes in.
关上所有的门! 去! 还有 Oaks 任何人不准进来
Very well.
很好
Well, Marshal...
呃 Marshal...
you got us our castle.
你帮我们拿下了城堡
- What is your strength, Captain?  - Eleven men-at-arms.
- 你有多少人 队长?  - 十一个全副武装的壮汉
- We have less than 20 men?  - And these walls.
- 我们只有不到20人?  - 还有这些城墙
- They've never been breached.  - Does the keep have a portcullis?
- 它们从未被攻破  - 塔楼里有升降闸门吗?
- It does.  - Good.
- 有  - 好的
- Once it's down, no one gets in.  - Water. Where is the supply?
- 放下它 没人能进来  - 还有水 水源在哪?
From the well. Draws straight from the river. No one here gets thirsty.
从水井里 直接从河里引来的 供给充足
- It's good, it's not sick or brackish?  - Water's good, sir.
- 很好 水源是干净 没有异味的吧?  - 水很好 先生
Guy, with me.
Guy 跟我来
These walls are designed to be defended by one man per station.
这些城墙都是一人一岗式设计
Outlook is perfect. Any approach can be seen for miles.
视野极佳 几英里外有敌来袭都可以看到
Now, let's see the gatehouse.
现在 去看看门楼
You, day or night, stay alert. Now open it up.
你 24小时保持警惕 现在开门
What's the problem?
有什么问题吗?
There's no moat.
没有壕沟
That'll do.
可以了
Now, when they come...
现在 敌人来袭...
hit them hard.
用力出击
Hit the post.
砍木桩
I said, hit the post. Hard.
我说了 砍这木桩 用力
They'll come? The French.
他们会来吗? 法国人
We waited for the French at Damascus. They didn't come then.
我们在大马士革(当时埃及首都)期待过法国人 他们没来
Even to a Frenchman I think Rochester is nearer than Damascus.
我想对法国人来说 罗彻斯特要比大马士革近
Hit it.
砍吧
You better hit it harder than that, boy.
孩子 你得砍得比我那下还狠
Or you'll be dead before they get here.
不然在法国人来之前你就挂了
They hate women.
他们讨厌女人
Just to look at one's a sin.
把女人当成一种罪恶
Some people say they worship the devil.
有人说他们崇拜魔鬼
Celibates with stone hearts.
铁石心肠 孤独终身
Then I have a stone heart, too, Maddy.
那我也是铁石心肠了 Maddy
I didn't mean it like that.
我不是那个意思
A Templar offers his chastity to God,
圣殿骑士把忠贞奉献给上帝
but a wife...
但妻子...
she suffers hers by her husband.
要把自己的忠贞奉献给丈夫
My husband's appetites don't include me.
我丈夫对我没有欲望
Thank the Lord Mary herself.
多谢圣母
Now, I am... curious, Albany.
Albany 现在 我... 很好奇
Why is it that you and your friends are so struck with this rebellion?
为什么你和你朋友们如此坚定地要反抗?
- Mm.  - Because we are for the people.
- 唔  - 因为我们是为了人民
I see your esquire is well-trained in the art of naivety.
我看你表现得十分天真嘛
- Go on.  - Call me naive if you will, sir,
- 继续  - 请尽管说我天真吧 先生
but the people deserve more than a king that treats them like animals.
但人民的国王 不应当是一个把他们当做牲畜的人
Ah, bold words for a Squire.
噢 一个护卫的无畏之言
Have you read Magna Carta?
你读过大宪章吗?
- I...  - Ah, I see. You can't read Latin.
- 我...  - 嗷 我知道了 你不懂拉丁文
It's a pity, arguing from ignorance.
真遗憾 无知的陈述
Argumentum ad ignorantiam, ab uno disce omnes.
人以群分
That's Roman, isn't it?
那是罗马话吧?
From one person, learn all people.
人以群分
Excuse my wife's bold tongue.
请原谅我妻子的冒失
Becket, I'm gonna need you on the far wall.
Becket 到最远的城墙去
- Guy can't defend it on his own.  - Do it yourself.
- Guy一个人守不住的  - 要去自己去
What?
什么?
You want a drink? A woman?
想喝酒? 还是想要女人?
Don't you sniff your nose at me?
不要总盛气凌人
I've been places. I've seen what your holy brothers have done.
我到过许多地方 见识过你圣洁的兄弟们做过什么
Your pious bile makes me sick.
你那虚伪的勇敢让我想吐
Becket. I want you outside.
Becket 出来
I'll watch your boy's back, but who's watching mine?
我会照顾你的小兄弟 但谁会照顾我的?
To the battlements!
上城垛!
- To the battlements!  - Right away!
- 上城垛!  - 马上!
- Take your positions, men!  - Get those men up here, quickly!
- 坚守岗位 伙计!  - 让那些人上来 快点!
Mercel, they're here!
Mercel 他们来了!
Let's see what rats have taken up in my home.
我们看看那些叛徒都在我家做了些什么
Move it! Come on!
移开它! 来!
Albany, a word. You cannot engage the King without considering terms.
Albany 我有话要说 你不能毫无理由就与国王交战
He wants our heads on spikes. Where are the terms in that?
他想杀了我们 这又有什么理由?
There are some in here who didn't pick this fight.
有人不想参加战斗
Ask yourself who you're for, Cornhill.
Cornhill 扪心自问 你要站在哪边
The King or the country? Because we both can't be wrong.
是国王还是国家? 我们都不能出错
They're here.
他们来了
Albany!
Albany 出来!
How did he know? What can we do for you, John?
他怎么知道我在这? 我们能为你做些什么 约翰?
Baron William de Albany.
William de Albany男爵
The Pope has ordered me to reclaim my country.
我奉教皇之命收回我的国家
Now, surely you don't bar your door against a king, and the church?
现在 你肯定不会把国王和教会拒之门外吧?
Does he know you sealed a charter...
他知道你签署了宪章...
giving the people of England freedom,
予英格兰人民以自由
and that now you go back on your word?
但是又想言而无信吗?
England is mine, Albany.
Albany 英格兰是我的
God's will bestowed it unto me, the Pope blesses it to me,
上帝将它赐予我 教皇为它祈福
and this castle belongs to me!
这城堡属于我!
You're no more a king...
你不是国王...
than the boil on my arse!
你臭名昭著!
What a tedious little man.
惹人厌的个小人
Get the swords now. Come on!
马上去拿剑 快!
Stay by your posts.
坚守岗位
Remember, they have to climb over these walls.
记住 他们要翻过城墙
And we do not.
但我们不用
So you stand firm!
所以守住!
Have you ever fought so many with so few?
你像这样以少敌多过吗?
Uh... huh. Don't you forget, you hold the wall, huh?
呃... 呼 别忘了 守住城墙 知道吗?
Now, go to your post.
现在 去你的岗位
North and south advance!
南北挺进!
Get ready, archers!
射手准备!
Loose!
放!
Take cover!
寻找掩护!
And again! Take cover!
再来! 寻找掩护!
Get down!
趴下!
Ha-ha!
哈哈!
Come on, lads, come on! Take your positions! Look lively!
快 小伙子 快! 坚守岗位! 打起精神来!
Take cover, lads! Take cover!
寻找掩护 小伙子! 寻找掩护!
Again!
再来!
Albany!
Albany注意!
Archers! They're coming!
射手! 他们来了!
Make a stand! Ready?
就位! 准备
Load arrows!
拉弓!
Loose!
放!
- Oil! Bring up that oil!  - Ready!
- 油! 把油拿上来!  - 预备!
Loose!
放!
- Oil!  - Watch your back!
- 油!  - 小心后面!
Take cover!
躲起来!
Becket!
Becket啊!
Come on. This way.
来 这边
- What do we do?  - Pray God is with them.
- 我们要做什么?  - 祈祷上帝保佑他们
Becket!
Becket啊!
Guy!
Guy 小心!
Show that to your mother!
给你妈看吧!
Now, get up!
现在 起来!
I said get up!
我说站起来!
Now, you hit him. Hard!
现在 去砍他 用力!
Behind you! Clear!
我在你们后面! 让开!
Take cover!
躲起来!
They're running!
他们跑了!
- They're retreating!  - They've had enough, Baron.
- 他们撤退了  - 他们伤亡惨重 男爵
Bastards! Go on, run!
杂种! 继续 快跑!
Come on, you foreign whores!
来啊 你们这些贱人!
You fought bravely.
你战斗英勇
You did not see everything.
有些事你并不知道
There's no finding peace after knowing this.
明白这点后 我觉得不会有和平的一天
Faith, Guy.
信念 Guy
Only the weak believe that what they do in battle...
只有弱者才会认为自己在战斗中的表现...
is who they are as men.
体现出了男子汉气概
Put him with the others.
和其他人放在一起
Pack them over there. Over there, that's it.
把他们放那 那 就那
Baron Albany...
Albany男爵...
in less than a day...
一天不到...
you have stripped away everything I gave the people in this castle.
你就夺去了 我给予城堡里的人们的一切
- Get off my back.  - You were hellbent on this fight!
- 走开  - 你在战斗中不顾一切!
You made us all hostages to your cause, not the rebellion's.
我们变成了你自己的人质 而不是反抗军的人质
And this was not just another castle!
这不仅仅是一个城堡!
This was my home!
这是我家!
Now clear your mess up.
给我打扫干净
Shut the door.
关门
Still now.
冷静下来
Wait. Here.
等等 过来
- This man is bleeding.  - On the table.
- 他在流血  - 躺到桌上
No. Wait. This will stop the flow.
不 等等 这样可以止血
I'm gonna pull this hard.
我会把这个拉紧
The bone's not broken, but...
没有骨折 不过...
Go on, do it, do it.
继续 来吧 来吧
Keep it clean, and watch him close.
保持清洁 好好照顾他
Templar.
圣殿骑士
- Your neck.  - No.
- 你的脖子  - 没事
Sit.
坐下
Please.
请
If the bleeding doesn't stop, shall I fasten a belt around your neck?
如果止不住血 我要不要给你脖子系根带子?
My maid tells me you cannot look at women.
我的侍女告诉我 你不能看女人
What is your name?
你叫什么?
Am I to assume your silence means you cannot talk to women either?
是不是可以认为 你沉默是因为你也不能和女人说话?
My name is Thomas Marshal.
我叫Thomas Marshal
There it is.
好了
And were many sacred vows broken by that revelation?
这次反叛是不是打破了很多神圣誓言?
It's not like the others. The river naturally defends.
这里和其他地方不同 河流是天然的防御屏障
Walls built... so a few can stop many.
高筑的城墙... 所以他们寡能敌众
Don't insult me, Captain.
别耍我了 队长
I know the qualities of a Norman keep.
我很了解诺曼要塞的情况
What I am having trouble with...
我不了解的是...
is how a thousand men could have failed so miserably against twenty.
我们千人的队伍怎么会被20人打得溃不成军
Those men fight hard. For what?
那些人拼了命地抵抗 为了什么?
A small rock in a field?
就为了荒野中这座小城堡?
We go around.
我们出去走走
My great, great grandfather built that rock
我的曾曾祖父在攻克这个国家后
when he conquered this country.
筑造了这座城堡
Strategically, it fortifies London and controls all of southern England.
它赋有战略意义 加强了伦敦的防御能力 并控制了英国的南部
Why in God's name do you think they chose to hole up there in the first place?
否则你以为 他们为什么一开始就选择了躲在那儿?
What will please your people more, Captain?
什么更能取悦你的部下 队长?
That your men died in a great battle,
是你的士兵在一场伟大战役中牺牲
or that your reward for helping me is the Church leaving your lands alone?
还是帮助我取得胜利后 教会允许让你的领地独立?
For that is what the Pope promised he would do.
那就是教皇承诺的条件
Now, however small it may seem...
虽然那座城堡看起来...
with that rock, the rest of this country follows.
很渺小 但它是决定这个国家命运的关键
Now you see what he means to do.
现在他想做什么 你们都看到了
I say this to each of you.
大家都听好了
There's a night out there...
外面夜正深...
deep enough for a man to slip away, if he should wish.
谁想逃跑 都完全可以趁着夜色离开
And I would understand.
我能理解
I think you upset him.
你吓到他了
What about you, Marks?
你呢 Marks?
I took this for you at Angouléme.
这是我在Angouléme时替你挨的
I walked into this outside Toulouse.
这是在图卢兹外受的伤
Both times we saw it through. What do you think I'm doing here?
那两次我们都熬过来了 你以为我来这儿做什么的?
I don't take a man's money and run.
我不会拿了人家的钱就跑的
Mr Phipps, are you and your garrison men still for the fight?
Phipps先生 您和您的驻军还会继续战斗吗?
All six of us. Good and ready, sir.
我们六人随时整装待发 阁下
I saw you with the Templar.
我看见你和那个圣殿骑士了
I think he has a mind for you.
我觉得他对你有意思
His mind possesses nothing I care to think about.
我没兴趣了解他对什么有意思
There is something not normal with him. It's his manner.
他有点不寻常 我是说他的礼仪方面
He looks but won't talk.
他看着人的时候就不会说话
Then he talks and nothing he says settles with me.
一说话就没有回旋的余地
Don't tell me that was his way before he became a Templar. I wouldn't believe it.
他在成为圣殿骑士前绝不是这样的 肯定不会是这样的
- My Lady.  - What?
- 夫人  - 怎么了?
That's a great deal of thinking...
对一个您没什么兴趣的人...
for someone you don't want to think about.
您想得其实很多了
They're building something.
他们在建什么东西
What do you think it is?
你觉得是什么?
Your royal engineer, Sire.
您的御用工程师 陛下
- Will it work?  - There's no moat, er... So, er...
- 这能行吗?  - 没有护城河 呃... 所以 呃...
There's no moat and no excuses. Finish it.
没有护城河就别找借口了 快点完工
I am sorry for what I said to you.
很抱歉我对你说了那些话
I was wrong.
我错了
What happens next... to us?
接下来 我们... 会发生什么?
- All of us?  - They will attack again.
- 我们所有人?  - 他们会再度发起攻击
And we will hold again.
而我们能再次守住
The French...
法国那边...
made sail with an army to stand by us.
已经有一支军队起航来支援我们了
You really believe they will come?
你真的相信他们会来?
Hm.
嗯
Thou shall not lie, Thomas.
你不该说谎的 Thomas
Certainly not for the French.
法国人肯定不会来的
Definitely not to me. It isn't worth it.
我觉得肯定不会的 不值得
Does that break Templar laws?
那样是否违背了圣殿骑士的规定?
Mm.
嗯
Some would say yes.
有人会说是的
Put the sword down.
把剑放下
If they do come, I will need to know how to use this.
如果他们真的来了 我得学会如何用剑
- Is this how you hold it?  - If you want your opponent to win.
- 你们是这样拿剑的?  - 如果你想让敌人赢的话
I fight...
我会战斗到底的...
so you don't have to.
所以你不必学会使剑
Siege tower.
是攻城塔楼
Making quick work of it. Damn it.
建得还挺快 该死
Baron, I have an idea.
男爵 我有个主意
What happens if this doesn't work?
这办法没用的话 怎么办?
- Don't ask.  - What could be worse than this?
- 别问了  - 还有什么能比这更糟的?
Squire, would you ever kill a woman?
护卫 你会杀女人吗?
- Never.  - Not even if it meant saving her life?
- 绝不  - 即使是为了救她?
That's it, heave it down.
就那样 斜下来
Holy Saint Joseph! Look who it is.
天堂圣徒约翰! 看看这是谁
His Majesty is ready, My Lord.
主啊 陛下准备就绪
- Prince Louis holds in France.  - They haven't sailed yet?
- Louis王子被困在法国了  - 他们还没起航?
- He's buying time to negotiate terms.  - Negotiate terms!
- 他在争取时间谈判  - 谈判!
The King enslaves this country,
国王奴役了整个国家
the Pope defends him and calls the Magna Carta heresy,
教皇还拥护他 判定大宪章违背教义
and France uses this tyranny for a better deal?
而法国还想从这暴政中获利?
- Are there any men willing to fight?  - A few.
- 有人愿意参与反叛吗?  - 不多
Many thought the rebellion was over because John signed the Magna Carta.
很多人认为叛乱已经结束了 因为约翰王已经签署了大宪章
In some ways, it was the smartest thing he did.
从某些方面来说 这是他做过最明智的事
Well, all that is done.
事已至此
Let Rome pronounce whatever holy dictum it pleases.
罗马那边乐意宣布什么神圣声明 都随他们去吧
They won't tell me that God is their possession.
反正他们也不能说 上帝归他们所有
I leave for France at once. You gather what men you can.
我立刻去法国 你们尽可能招兵买马
And prepare London for war.
准备好伦敦一战
And Rochester?
那罗彻斯特城堡呢?
- Baron Albany?  - Pray God is with them.
- Baron男爵吗?  - 愿上帝与他们同在
Take cover!
寻找掩护!
Excellent. Excellent.
很好 很好
Go on. Faster!
继续 快点!
Lock it!
固定住!
- Lock!  - And fire!
- 固定!  - 发射!
They have built an engine?
他们建了个发射器?
Take cover!
寻找掩护!
All of you, outside.
所有人 出去
Wulfstan, you've broken through!
Wulfstan 你乱了他们的阵脚!
Now, come on! Give them hellfire!
来吧! 给他们来一炮!
Heave! Heave!
拉呀! 拉呀!
Lock it! Fire pot, Guy!
固定! 火罐 Guy!
You heathen dogs!
你们这群野狗!
Bring it a bit forward!
往前来点!
Light it! Light it!
点燃它! 点燃它!
Loose!
发射!
Goddamn devils! Murdering goddamn whores!
该死的混蛋! 把那群婊子养的给我宰了!
Yes! They burn!
中了! 烧起来了!
Do not record that!
不许记下来!
Bitches!
混蛋!
This bastard king, Wulfstan.
那个暴君 Wulfstan
Aye.
是啊
After that, the king did not come again.
那之后 国王没有再来了
But the rains did.
然而雨来了
And the days grew short as autumn turned to winter.
秋去冬来 白昼越来越短
They were too cold to fight, and too hungry.
人们又饿又冷 无法应战
The castle stores were empty...
城堡内的存粮也空了...
and they had taken to eating the horses.
他们开始吃马匹
Save for one.
只剩下了一匹
Marshal's.
是Marshal的
But a Templar is forbidden to eat his horse.
但圣殿骑士不能吃自己的战马
Their order dictates that it must die in battle.
他们的规定是 战马只能死于战场上
So 13 hungry souls and one horse would remain.
所以剩下了13个饥肠辘辘的人和一匹马
Still they waited.
他们仍在等待
And so too did the King.
国王也是如此
They could smell his food, hear his army's song.
他们可以闻到他食物的味道 听见他军队的歌声
For attrition is one man's ally and another man's curse.
耗损的是一方的齐心协力和另一方的诅咒连连
So they became cursed men.
所以他们成了被诅咒的人
And as weeks turned to months,
时光飞逝
their minds took to places they should not...
他们的思想开始变得消极...
where a man sees only doubt and has no worth at all.
对一切只剩怀疑 不再有任何期许
On my wedding day I knew my marriage would have no love.
我婚礼那天 我就知道我的婚姻没有爱情
Yet still I took my vows to God.
但我仍向上帝发了誓
I honoured and obeyed my commitments daily.
每日 我都信守诺言 遵守诺言
You think we are not the same, Thomas, but you're wrong.
你以为我们不同 Thomas 但你错了
- I'm starving!  - What do you want me to do?
- 我饿死了!  - 你想让我怎么办?
Someone's gotta do something!
总得有人做点什么!
Listen to me.
听着
Damn your Templar vows!
让你圣殿骑士的誓言见鬼去吧!
It was my vows that made me what I am.
是我的誓言告诉我怎样做人
It was my order that brought me here.
是我的使命带我来到了这里
And by God's good grace,
在主的保佑下
it will be the Templars that save your life.
将由圣殿骑士们来拯救你们
Where are you going?
你要去哪?
Why are you leaving?
你为什么要离开?
Why would he leave?
他为什么离开?
My Lady, you were with him last.
夫人 您最后跟他在一起
Did he say why he left?
他有说为什么离开吗?
You go to your chamber.
回你的房间去
Now.
现在
No.
不
I'll kiss the Bishop's arse if he comes back.
只要他能回来 我什么都愿意做
You're gonna have to kiss a king's arse, Becket, cos they're coming back again.
那你有的事做了 Becket 他们又来了
- It's Thomas!  - Open the gates!
- 是Thomas!  - 打开大门!
Becket, get him! Get him, Becket!
Becket 去接他! 接他 Becket!
- Come on! Quickly! Help him!  - Get the sacks. The sacks!
- 去啊! 快点! 帮帮他!  - 把袋子捡起来 捡袋子!
- Come on!  - Hurry!
- 来啊!  - 快点!
- Run!  - Close the portcullis!
- 快跑!  - 关上闸门!
What was you thinking, Templar?
你想做什么啊 骑士?
He's stolen the King's food. I've never seen such a thing!
他偷了国王的粮食 我从没见过这种事!
You are relieved of your command, Captain.
我解除你的任命 队长
Get back in your rowboat and go home.
回你的小船上去 滚回家吧
- I'm not leaving without my men!  - Oh yes, you are!
- 我不会扔下我的部下离开的!  - 噢 不可能 你必须走!
And I will tell you why. The Pope has had a change of heart.
我来告诉你为什么 教皇改变心意了
What do you say?
你说什么?
I say that when your pathetic little army arrives back at your houses,
我说等你那点可怜的军队回到家乡的时候
you will find your lands Christianised.
你会发现你的土地已经皈依基督教了
Your sons enslaved to the Church and your wives serving new husbands.
你们的子女受制于教会 你们的妻子早已令嫁新人
You did not speak to the Pope of my lands?
你没有和教皇说过让我的领地独立?
Why in God's name would I do that?
我到底为什么要那样做?
Take this castle, Tiberius!
攻下这座城堡 Tiberius!
And if you do not, you will be sailing home to quite a different world.
如果你没做到 漂洋过海回家后 将看到一个完全不同的世界
Well, Marshal, you sure know how to pick a bit of shank.
Marshal 你显然很会挑偷袭的时机
Better than three months of horse meat.
比吃三个月的马肉好多了
- I'll stick with the pig.  - Then what?
- 我还要猪肉  - 然后呢?
I'll eat you.
我会把你吃了
So, Squire...
护卫...
you can read words?
你认字吗?
And write them too?
还会写?
What's your full name?
你的全名是什么?
Jedediah Coteral.
是Jedediah Coteral
读作Jedediah Coteral
Jedediah Coteral.
Jedediah Coteral啊
Yeah.
是啊
I've never seen it written before. Huh.
我从未见过它的写法
It's too quiet. Check the far wall.
太安静了 去查看下远墙
To the battlements! Attack!
到城垛了! 有人袭击!
Cover the west wing. West wing! Come on!
掩护西翼 西翼! 快点!
- Watch out!  - To the right!
- 注意!  - 到右边去!
Help me!
帮帮我!
The gates! The gates!
大门! 大门!
Where's Marshal?
Marshal在哪?
Fight, Guy! Fight!
上啊 Guy! 上啊!
Baron!
男爵!
Don't move. Be still.
别动 别动
- Hold the keep.  - You can't die.
- 守住要塞  - 你不能死
You can't die. Stay alive! You hear me?
你不能死 活下去! 听见了吗?
Hold the keep! Go! Go!
守住要塞! 去啊! 去啊!
Phipps!
Phipps 来啊!
- Come here!  - Hold the gates!
- 来这里!  - 守住大门!
I've got it. I've got it.
我来了 我来了
Come on, to the gates!
快点 来大门这!
Hold!
守住!
All in! All in!
全部过来! 全部过来!
Stand fast!
别后退!
Shield wall!
组成盾墙!
Shields. Shields up!
防守 举起盾牌!
Up!
举起来!
Brace yourselves.
做好准备
Ready! Ready!
准备好了! 准备好了!
- Isabel!  - Get inside!
- Isabel!  - 进去!
Now!
马上!
- We have to get to the Baron!  - To the keep!
- 我们得去找男爵!  - 去要塞!
- We can't leave him!  - He's gone, all right?
- 我们不能把他丢下!  - 他死了 知道吗?
Hold the steps! Hold the steps!
守住楼梯! 守住楼梯!
Come on!
快过来!
Marshal!
是Marshal!
Pull him down!
拉他下马!
- Marshal!  - Come on!
- Marshal!  - 快走啊!
Get it off! Get it off!
快脱下来! 脱下来!
Get back, behind the portcullis!
过来 到铁闸门后面来!
Come on!
过来啊!
They have prisoners.
他们抓到俘虏了
Boy!
小厮!
Good afternoon, Baron. Did you find my castle to your liking?
下午好啊 男爵 我的城堡还合你的意吗?
It's the people's castle now.
城堡现在属于大家了
You said he was gone.
你说他死了的
Those two. Cut off their hands and feet.
这两个 把他们手脚剁了
- No. - No!
- 不  - 别这样!
No!
不!
不要!
Now, Baron, I want my keep back.
现在 男爵 我要夺回我的要塞
- At my command!  - No!
- 受我统辖!  - 不!
- They'll never surrender.  - Really?
- 他们绝不会投降  - 绝不?
Do it!
剁了!
- Do something!  - We hold the keep.
- 快做点什么啊!  - 我们得守住要塞
My arse, your stinking castle!
去你妈的狗屁城堡!
God damn you, you murdering whore!
你这该死的 没人性的臭婊子!
Isn't that the king I am?
我可不就是这样一个国王吗?
You betray all that's meant to be king.
你背弃了王者二字的真意
You betray God!
你背叛了上帝!
I betray God?!
我背叛了上帝?!
My crown was passed to me by my brother, and my father before him.
我兄长从我父王手中夺取了王位 之后又传位于我
I was born to be a king!
我是天生的国王!
It is my birthright! Given to me by God!
我才是真命天子! 天命所授!
You cry for the common man
你为平民呐喊
and in the same breath you curse the crown that protects him!
却又诅咒着保护他们的王者!
You dare to question my reign...
你竟敢质疑我的王位...
and the lineage of Kings who have reigned before me?!
质疑列位先王时代相传的王室血统?!
The great amaranthine royalty of Aquitaine...
我伟大 不朽的阿基坦王室
Who forged this land from barbarian horde
是谁将这片土地从野蛮部落
and made it noble and pure!
教化得如此高贵 纯净!
Who gave it order, meaning,
是谁带来了秩序 意义
and even faith...
甚至信仰...
to thousands of years of loyal subjects!
乃至千百年来的忠诚!
And it is all now questioned by you!
现在你却来质疑这一切!
And we are forced to sign your precious Magna Carta,
我们被迫签下你视若珍宝的大宪章
forced by you, a wool merchant!
被你 一个卖羊毛的 逼迫!
I am the blood! I am God's right hand!
我才是王室正宗! 我才是上帝的右手!
And you will never dictate to me how I am to be a king!
你有何德何能来发号施令 教我怎么当国王!
Now, Baron.
现在 男爵
Which hand did you touch me with?
你当时用哪只手逼我的?
Hold his hand down.
把他的手压在桩子上
Hold his right hand down!
把他的右手压在桩子上!
This is not something you should see.
这些不该让你看到的
Tell your rebels to open the gate, Albany!
让你的同伙把门打开 Albany!
No surrender!
宁死不屈!
- No surrender!  - Put his other hand up! Do it!
- 宁死不屈!  - 把另一手也绑起来! 动手!
Do it!
快!
We hold, Baron!
我们会守住的 男爵!
We hold!
会守住的!
Put his feet up. Put his feet up!
把他的脚剁了 给我剁了!
Cornhill!
Cornhill啊!
You will yield to your king!
你若不向你的国王屈服!
Or, as God hears me, your head is on a spike!
我向上帝发誓 必将你的头颅钉在长钉之上!
Now, that monster that they've made, strap his carcass to it.
把他的尸体吊到他们造出来的那怪物上去!
Strap him to it!
吊上去!
Heave!
发射!
There's no one coming, is there?
根本就没有增援 是吗?
My scouts report the French have left Calais.
侦察兵来报 法国人已经从加莱起航了
They'll be at our back within days.
数天之后就会抵达我们的后方
Do you know that when I was a child,
你知道吗 当我还是个孩子时
I once secretly ate every urn of my father's beloved honey peaches.
有一次 我偷偷吃光了我父亲最喜欢的水蜜桃
And the next day...
第二天...
he brought before me a servant girl that he had accused of the crime.
他把一个女仆带到我面前 责骂她吃光了桃子
And he placed her hand on the table, and he drew his knife...
之后 他把她的手按在桌子上 拔出刀...
and he delivered the punishment.
然后就地行刑
And that night, unable to contain my shame,
那天晚上 我羞愧得无以自容
I confessed to him that it was I,
我向父亲坦白 那是我所为
his son, who had committed the crime.
是他的儿子做的坏事
Do you know what his response was?
你知道他怎么回答我的吗?
He said, "I know.
他说"我知道"
I know.
我是知道的
And that is why I only cut off her finger.
所以我只砍掉了她的手指
You see, John, any action against the throne
听好了 约翰 任何威胁王座的行为
must be punished ruthlessly.
都必须毫不容情地惩罚
For that is the only way to maintain the absolute power...
这是维护国王绝对君权的...
of a king."
唯一之计"
When they come, you must demand to see the King.
要是他们闯进来 你一定要要求面见约翰王
I want nothing from him.
我和他无话可说
Not even mercy.
更不会请他手下留情
I broke my vow, Isabel.
我已经违背了誓言 Isabel
I have betrayed God's trust.
辜负了主对我的信任
What we did was a sin.
我们的所为是罪孽
Stop hiding... behind vows and commandments.
不要再躲在... 誓言和戒律的背后了
The vows speak of loyalty and abstinence and murder, but...
那些誓言里只有忠诚 节欲 还有谋杀 但是
why never love, Thomas?
为什么从不提爱情 Thomas?
The vows of the order...
我许下的誓言...
protect my soul from the blood I've spilt in God's name.
让我以主之名犯下的杀戮 不会污染我的灵魂
It was the Church that made you do those things.
逼你做这些事的是教会
It was the Templars that gave you a sword
将剑交到你手中的 让你以主之名举剑的
and the name of God to wield it.
是圣殿骑士
It was the Templars that made you kill.
让你去屠杀的是圣殿骑士
Who were you before them?
而在成为圣殿骑士前 你是什么人?
What was so bad about that man then that makes you resist your desires now?
之前的你有多罪大恶极 让你现在这样抗拒自己真心所愿?
Thomas...
Thomas啊...
I am not a sin.
我不是罪恶
Sire? Sire?
陛下? 陛下?
Your engineer, sire. The mine is ready.
工程师来报 陛下 坑道准备好了
Will it work?
会有用吗?
It's right under the keep's foundations.
坑道就在要塞地基的下面
Then take note.
记下来
To my justiciar, send to me 40 pigs.
给最高司法官送信 要他送来40头猪
The least good for eating.
能吃就行
Deliver that at once.
快马加鞭地送去
Come on! Hurry up! Move it!
走啊! 快点! 往前走啊!
That's it.
够了
- Where you going?  - I'm going to plead for terms.
- 你要去哪里?  - 我要去签署条款
No!
不行!
- What else is there to do don't you see?  - We hold.
- 你看不出已经没有其他出路了吗?  - 只能守住这里
We hold for what? The French? They're not coming.
我们守着城堡做什么? 等法国人? 他们根本不会来
- I'll ask for terms. - No!
- 我现在就去签  - 不行!
We swore an oath. An oath!
我们起过誓了 誓言不可违!
To Albany. To England.
效忠Albany 效忠英格兰
Your oath is worthless.
你的誓言一钱不值
Magna Carta is worthless.
大宪章也是一钱不值
The Church has annulled it.
教会已经废止了"大宪章"
Whatever happens here is meaningless.
这里发生的一切都毫无意义
No. No. Wait!
不 别 等等!
- That's enough, Squire.  - Becket?
- 够了 护卫  - Becket?
Your boy here tried to take the old man's head off.
你的部下正打算把老家伙的脑袋拧下来
Becket, leave him be.
Becket 放开他
Now, Guy... get away from him.
Guy... 放开他 马上
- Now.  - Or what?
- 马上  - 不然呢?
You'll kill me?
你就杀了我?
- Guy...  - Shut up!
- Guy...  - 闭上嘴!
Baron de Albany gave his life for his beliefs.
de Albany男爵为了自己的信仰献出了生命
What have you given for yours?
你献出过什么?
Coward.
懦夫
There's no salvation to this end.
事情已经无可挽回了
Our souls...
我们都要...
are damned.
万劫不复了
You are not a coward.
你不是个懦夫
- What are you doing?  - I'm writing my name.
- 你做什么呢?  - 写自己的名字
How do you do that?
你怎么会写的?
Master Guy taught me.
Guy小师傅教我的
Well, that's you all done then.
嗯 你也就只能做做这个了
What makes a man like you so angry?
你为什么老是这么怒气冲冲的?
I've been angry so long...
我已经这样很久了...
I don't even remember.
甚至都记不起为什么了
It's kept you alive though, I suppose.
我猜 你就靠这个活到现在的
I don't think it's gonna get us through this one.
我觉得 这样不能帮我们熬过这次
- What do you think they're doing?  - Pigs. For a sapper's fire.
- 你觉得他们这是要干什么?  - 那些猪 为了在坑道里点火的
- Sappers?  - They're digging a mine underneath us.
- 坑道?  - 他们在我们下面挖坑呢
Pig's fat, it burns, with the heat of a crucible.
猪的油脂多 用坩埚加热后 就开始燃烧
Make Way!
让路!
Go on! Go!
走啊! 快!
Whoa there!
吁 停!
Bring them in.
把它们赶进去
We've got a bigger problem.
我们有更大的麻烦了
Hah! Get in there!
呀! 给我进去!
Go on!
进去!
Coteral.
Coteral啊
It's hot.
很烫手
So what are we gonna do now? Templar.
我们接下去怎么办? 圣殿骑士
We get to the other side of the keep.
我们到要塞的另一侧
Guy, take the women to the chapel, huh?
Guy 把女人都带到小礼堂去 嗯?
Go!
去啊!
Hurry, Isabel.
快来 Isabel
Get down! Get down!
趴下! 快趴下!
- I think he's gone.  - I'm not making that mistake again.
- 我看他已经没命了  - 我可不打算再犯那种错
Come on.
来啊
OK. One, two.
好 一 二 起
Oh, Maddy. She was beside me.
Maddy呢 她刚才还在我身边的
Becket. Becket.
Becket. Becket啊.
I'll hold them off.
我拖住他们
How much did they pay to get you out those stocks?
他们花了多少钱从枷锁下救出了你?
- Five shillings.  - That is cheaper than a whore.
- 五先令  - 比妓女还便宜
Come on, you filthy whores!
来啊 你们这些臭婊子!
If they get through us, you kill the women.
如果我们没挡住他们 你就把女人都杀了
- No.  - Say it.
- 不  - 答应我
- I can't.  - Say it!
- 我不行  - 答应啊!
I'll kill the women.
我会把女人都杀了
Come on, you whore!
来啊 你们这些婊子!
Forgive me.
原谅我
Thomas. Thomas!
Thomas. Thomas啊!
Thomas!
Thomas啊!
Save her.
救她
No one touch him!
都别碰他!
How's your faith now, Templar?
现在你的信念呢 圣殿骑士?
Why don't you come a little closer...
不如你过来点...
and I'll show you.
我让你好好看看
You fought bravely.
你作战很英勇
Is killing a noble thing?
杀戮是件高尚的事吗?
But a life fought for others is a life worth living.
为他人而战 才不枉一生
That is a noble thing.
才是高尚的事
A French prince now holds the English crown.
现在一个法国王子登上了英国的王座
Not an easy decision to make.
这是个艰难的决定
Nor was this one.
还有一个决定也是
The Order's over for you, Thomas.
你不再属于教会了 Thomas
You've earned your freedom as much as any man.
你现在享有和他人一样的人身自由
Your Grace.
多谢您的恩典
Come on.
走吧
We held.
我们守住了
Within a year, the rebellion was won.
在一年之内 反叛军取得了胜利
While fleeing for his life, King John died of dysentery.
约翰王在逃亡的路上死于痢疾
What was left of his treasure was never recovered.
而他留下的宝藏从此失去了下落
In time, the great keep of Rochester was rebuilt.
同时 重建了罗彻斯特城堡
It stands to this day.
这座城堡屹立至今
So too does the noble dream that was... Magna Carta.
大宪章... 这个高贵的梦想也同样如此
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：岸
翻译：RK翔  onebyone Ivy 发条橙
校对：不想论文的微  不想工作的岸